<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 1999-2005 The Apache Software Foundation
Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<!--
// ======================================================================== 78
-->
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Announcements</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Announcements">

            <h4 id="a20060628.1">28 Jun 2006 - Shale to Become Top-Level
                ASF Project</h4>            
            <p>
               On behalf of the ASF Board and Struts PMC, we are pleased to
               announce that Shale has been accepted as a top-level project of
               the Apache Software Foundation.
            </p>
            <p>
               As a top-level project, Shale will have its own website, mailing
               lists, repository space, and Project Management Committee. Shale
               will be an automomous ASF project, rather than a subproject of
               Apache Struts.
            </p>
            <p>
               The Shale framework for JavaServer Faces is nearing its first
               stable release. As a top-level project, it will be easier for
               Shale to attract new developers and expand its growing community.
            </p>
            <p>
               The initial set of PMC members and committers for Shale is:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Craig McClanahan
                </li>
                <li>
                    James Mitchell
                </li>
                <li>
                    Greg Reddin
                </li>
                <li>
                    Sean Schofield
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wendy Smoak
                </li>
                <li>
                    Gary VanMatre
                </li>
                <li>
                    Matthias Wessendorf
                </li>
            </ul>

            <p>
               Apache Shale has strong ties to both the Struts and MyFaces
               projects. Most of the Shale PMC members are already involved
               in both projects, and plan on continuing to remain involved in
               them, along with Shale.
            </p>
            <p>
               Apache Shale is a modern web application framework, intended for
               developers adopting JavaServer Faces as a core technology.
            </p>
            <p>
               Shale began as a proposal for Struts 2.0, but instead became a
               subproject, so as to provide a JSF alternative for Struts
               developers. Recent developments for Struts 2 now make it
               easier for Struts developers to access JSF components from within
               an "action-based" application.
            </p>
            <p>
               The initial Shale codebase was donated by Craig McClanahan, who
               also donated the original Struts codebase.
            </p>
            <hr/>
        
            <h4 id="a20060603.3">03 Jun 2006 - New Struts Committer: 
            	Bob Lee</h4>            
            <p>
		Please join us in welcoming Bob Lee as a new Struts committer. 
            </p>
            <p>
		Some of us have known Bob for several years through his Struts, 
		WebWork, and Dynaop work, or in person from a conference. 
		At this last JavaOne, he met other PMC members: Craig, Martin, 
		Gary, and Wendy -- and Bob is well known to the WebWork folks.
            </p>
            <p>
		Bob's current focus is to develop a kinder, gentler API for 
		Struts 2, having already submitted several patches and 
		<a href="http://wiki.apache.org/struts/RoughSpots">
		constructively engaged the community</a> 
		while handling criticisms well. He has committed several 
		patches for WebWork and Xwork, started the Dynaop project, 
		and has been peripherally involved in the Struts community 
		for many years.  
            </p>
            <p>
		Welcome, Bob  ... Our only worry is that we haven't yet seen 
		the Crazy part of Crazy Bob.
            </p>
            <p>
		PMC vote: 8 +1 (binding), 4 +1 (non-binding).            
            </p>
            <hr/>
            
            <h4 id="a20060603.2">03 Jun 2006 - New Struts Committer: Michael 
            	Jouravlev</h4>            
            <p>
		Please join us in welcoming Michael Jouravlev as a new Struts 
		committer. 
            </p>
            <p>
		Michael has been an active member of our community for a very 
		long time. His posts to user@ and dev@ are consistently 
		helpful. Michael often participates in development 
		discussions, including the Action2 discussions. He has 
		<a href="http://tinyurl.com/ls7ga">
		submitted code and patches and collaborated on changes</a> 
		that were accepted to the code base.
            </p>
            <p>
		Michael has also make many contributions to the wiki, 
		including reorganizing the area so that it is more useful to 
		others.
            </p>
            <p>
		Welcome, Michael ... Just don't start downsizing the fonts :)
            </p>
            <p>
		PMC vote: 7 +1.            
            </p>
            <hr/>

            <h4 id="a20060603.1">03 Jun 2006 - New Struts Committer: Paul 
            	Benedict</h4>
            <p>
		Please join us in welcoming Paul Benedict as a new Struts 
		committer. 
	    </p>
	    <p>
	    	Paul has been an earnest and helpful member of our community 
	    	for well over a year now. He has submitted patches and ideas, 
	    	andvmany useful posts to the user list. Paul was particularly 
		active in the 
		<a href="http://issues.apache.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=38374">
		discussion</a> 
		that lead to the addition of the "Opt-in Cancel" feature, 
	    </p>
	    <p>
		In this and other discussions, Paul has demonstrated an 
		ability to collaborate with others and create a better 
		solution than the one originally proposed. 
 	    </p>
	    <p>
		Welcome, Paul ... Hey, we're always looking for release
		managers! 
 	    </p>
	    <p>
	    	PMC vote: 3 +1.
 	    </p>
            <hr/>
            
            <h4 id="a20050328">23 Mar 2006 - Struts Shale Framework 1.0.2 Alpha</h4>
            <p>
                The Struts team is pleased to announce the release of Struts Shale 1.0.2 Alpha.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://struts.apache.org/downloads.html">
                        http://struts.apache.org/downloads.html</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                The Struts Shale Framework is a set of loosely coupled services,
                fundamentally based on JavaServer Faces, which may be combined as
                needed to meet particular application requirements.
            </p>
            <p>
                Compared to version 1.0.0 (version 1.0.1 was retired due to packaging
                issues), this version includes a substantial number of bugfixes and
                enhancements -- details are in the Release Notes -- and the following
                major new features:
            </p>

            <ul>
                <li>
                    Shale Remoting is a complete overhaul of the remoting support in
                    1.0.0, providing support for application or component developers who
                    need to implement the server side behavior for AJAX callbacks. It is
                    packaged as a small (40k) JAR that has no dependencies on the rest of
                    Shale.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Tiger Extensions is an optional add-on layer for those running on
                    Java SE 5 (code named "Tiger"). The extensions let you use Java
                    annotations to declare managed beans or register JSF components,
                    without needing entries in a faces-config.xml file.
                </li>
                <li>
                    A new "blank" starter application to get you up and running with a
                    new project quickly.
                </li>
                <li>
                    A new "mailreader" demo application that duplicates the
                    functionality of the Struts 1.x version of this app, so you can
                </li>
                <li>
                    A new "SQL Browser" demo application that illustrates use of the
                    Tiger Extensions, as well as the ability to modify JSF component trees
                    on the fly.
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                Although this is considered an alpha release, various developer APIs
                should be considered at a more stable (in terms of assurances of
                backwards compatibility in future releases) point than might otherwise
                be expected. Please see the following web page for more details:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://struts.apache.org/struts-shale/api-stability.html">
                        http://struts.apache.org/struts-shale/api-stability.html</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <hr/>

            <h4 id="a20050322">22 Mar 2006 - Struts 1.2.9 (General
                Availability)</h4>
            <p>
                The Struts team is pleased to announce the release of Struts
                1.2.9 for General Availability. This release is primarily to
                <a href="http://www.frsirt.com/english/advisories/2006/1205">fix three security issues</a> 
                which have been identified and supersedes the earlier 1.2.8 version as
                the latest official release of Struts from The Apache Software
                Foundation.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more information on the security issues and solutions
                please see the
                <a href="http://struts.apache.org/1.2.9/userGuide/release-notes.html">
                    Release Notes</a>
                and the
                <a href="http://wiki.apache.org/struts/StrutsUpgrade">
                    Upgrade Notes</a>
            </p>
            <p>
                The binary, source and library distributions are available
                from the Struts
                download page:
                <a href="http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi">
                    http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi</a>
            </p>
            <hr/>

            <h4 id="a20060125.1">25 Jan 2006 - Struts Scripting 1.0.1
                Released</h4>
            <p>
                The Struts team is pleased to announce the release of Struts
                Scripting
                1.0.1 for General Availability. This is the first stable
                release of
                Struts Scripting (formerly Struts BSF). It allows Struts
                Actions to be
                written in the scripting language of one's choice rather than
                as Java
                classes. It uses the Bean Scripting Framework to allow scripts
                to be
                written in any language BSF supports like Perl, Python, Ruby,
                JavaScript, Groovy, and even VBScript.
            </p>
            <p>
                The binary and source distributions are available from the
                Struts
                download page:
                <a href="http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi">
                    http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi</a>
            </p>
            <p>
                You can find out more information about Struts Scripting at
                <a href="http://struts.apache.org/struts-scripting/">
                    http://struts.apache.org/struts-scripting/</a>
                .
            </p>
            <hr/>


            <h4 id="a20060117.1">17 Jan 2006 - New Struts Committers: Jason
                Carreira
                and Patrick Lightbody</h4>
            <p>
                Please join me in welcoming Jason Carreira and Patrick
                Lightbody as new
                Struts committers. Jason and Patrick are the core WebWork 2
                developers
                and they are joining us in an important step in the merger
                process. I, and
                many other Struts committers, have personally met and talked
                at length with
                both Patrick and Jason on several occasions and find them
                dedicated,
                skilled, and team players. Their dedication to WebWork 2 over
                the years is
                a testament to their perseverance, commitment to their
                community, and
                technical skill. We look forward to their contributions as
                committers.
            </p>

            <p>
                Welcome Jason and Patrick!
            </p>
            <p>
                PMC vote: 8 +1
            </p>
            <hr/>

        </section>

        <section>
            <p class="right">
                <a href="announce-2005.html">Announcements - 2005</a>
            </p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <p class="right">
                <strong>Next:</strong>
                <a href="faqs.html">Frequently Asked Questions</a>
            </p>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>
